Help!
Tolong!
Su Ruo
Su Ruo
The body was only found at six this morning.
Mayat baru ditemukan jam enam pagi ini.
This is an old neighborhood.
Ini kompleks lama.
There aren't many cameras outside.
Jadi CCTV di luar sedikit.
Every time you travel back in time,
Setiap kali kembali ke masa lalu,
the world you were in before
dunia tempatmu sebelumnya
becomes
akan berubah menjadi
a parallel world you abandoned.
dunia paralel yang kau tinggalkan.
Su Ruo
Su Ruo
Stay alive.
Bertahanlah.
Sir,
Pak.
you requested Chinese therapeutic massage.
Layanan yang Anda pesan adalah pijat terapi Tiongkok.
It helps with circulation and relieves fatigue.
Bisa melancarkan darah dan mengurangi lelah.
You can close your eyes.
Anda bisa menutup mata.
My name is Yu Xingchen.
Nama saya Yu Xingchen.
I'm just an ordinary researcher.
Saya peneliti biasa saja.
After revising papers for three days straight,
Setelah tiga hari revisi makalah berturut-turut,
I can finally relax for a bit.
saya bisa santai sebentar.
Weihaoke's "That Year"
"Weihaoke - Tahun Itu"
really captured the voice of youth.
Benar-benar menyuarakan masa muda.
I wonder if you ever sometimes
Tak tahu apakah kadang-kadang
think of that person you liked.
kau teringat seseorang itu.
Sorry, are you hurt?
Maaf, Anda cedera?
I was grading students' papers recently,
Belakangan saya revisi makalah mahasiswa.
stayed up several nights.
Begadang beberapa malam.
That's really bad for your health.
Itu sangat buruk untuk tubuh.
Like when you saved up a week's homework,
Dulu suka menumpuk PR seminggu
and tried to finish it all overnight.
dan dikerjakan dengan begadang.
Who could handle that?
Siapa yang kuat begitu?
We had a classmate like that too.
Dulu di kelas kami juga ada teman
He never did homework at night,
yang selalu tak kerjakan PR malam hari.
and copied it before morning class.
Pagi-pagi sebelum pelajaran, dia menyalin.
I was like that too.
Saya juga begitu.
What was that classmate's name?
Siapa nama teman itu ya?
I think it was
Sepertinya namanya
Yu Xingchen.
Yu Xingchen.
Su Ruo
Su Ruo
Yu Xingchen,
Yu Xingchen
long time no see.
Lama tak bertemu.
Her name is Su Ruo.
Namanya Su Ruo.
She was my classmate in high school.
Dia teman sekelas saya di SMA.
She was outstanding in both character and academics.
Berprestasi dan berakhlak baik.
Talented and beautiful.
Cantik dan pintar.
She was the girl I never dared to pursue.
Gadis yang dulu tak pernah saya berani dekati.
Su Ruo
Su Ruo
All these years,
Selama bertahun-tahun ini,
you've been working here?
kamu selalu kerja di sini?
Yeah.
Iya.
It's been many years.
Sudah bertahun-tahun.
Must be tough.
Pasti berat, ya?
Everything's tough these days.
Sekarang kerja apa pun berat.
By the way, Yu Xingchen,
Oh iya, Yu Xingchen.
do you still like me?
Kamu masih suka aku?
Just asking casually.
Aku cuma tanya saja.
Why are you so nervous?
Kenapa kamu tegang begitu?
My time's up.
Waktuku sudah habis.
I can extend the session.
Aku bisa tambah waktu.
No need.
Tak perlu.
You can sleep a bit more.
Tidur lagi saja.
You can close your eyes.
Kamu bisa tutup mata.
Close them.
Tutup.
Thanks for your hard work.
Kerja keras, ya.
I'm heading out.
Aku pergi dulu.
Could you please
Tolong ya,
give this umbrella
antarkan payung ini
to the guest in room 227?
ke tamu kamar 227.
Sure.
Baik.
Sir,
Pak.
Therapist No. 12 asked me to tell you
Terapis nomor 12 titip pesan
she left after her shift.
dia sudah pulang duluan.
Sir, here you go.
Pak, ini untuk Anda.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
Confession.
Menyatakan cinta.
One year after school, with everyone egging me on,
Suatu tahun, sepulang sekolah, didorong teman-teman,
I planned to confess to her.
aku berniat menyatakan cinta padanya.
Confession.
Menyatakan cinta.
But I lowered my head in front of her,
Tapi di depannya aku menunduk
stammered for five minutes without getting to the point.
dan gagap lima menit, tak berani bicara.
Confession.
Menyatakan cinta.
Until more and more people gathered around.
Sampai makin banyak yang menonton.
Do you have something to say to me?
Kamu mau bicara sesuatu padaku?
There's no one here now.
Sekarang tak ada orang.
You can say it.
Kamu bisa bicara.
I...
Aku...
I want to tell you...
Aku ingin bilang...
Are you trying to say you like me?
Kamu mau bilang suka aku, ya?
Okay, I get it.
Baik, aku tahu.
You're a guy,
Kamu kan laki-laki.
if you like someone in the future,
Kalau nanti suka seseorang,
just say it.
bilang saja langsung.
I'll go now.
Aku pergi dulu.
To her,
Bagi dia,
I was just one of many boys who liked her.
aku cuma salah satu dari banyak yang mengejarnya.
Her "I get it"
Kalimat "Aku tahu" itu
was a polite and friendly rejection.
adalah penolakan sopan dan ramah.
So after graduation,
Jadi setelah lulus,
my timid self never contacted her again.
aku yang penakut tak pernah menghubunginya lagi.
Who would've thought, after fifteen years,
Tak disangka lima belas tahun berlalu,
we'd meet again like this.
kami bertemu lagi dengan cara seperti ini.
By the way, Yu Xingchen,
Oh iya, Yu Xingchen.
do you still like me?
Kamu masih suka aku?
I do.
Suka.
Yes, I do.
Suka, suka banget.
Of course I do.
Tentu saja suka.
I do.
Suka.
It's me.
Ini aku.
I had a meeting last night,
Tadi malam aku ada urusan
so I missed your call.
jadi tak sempat angkat teleponmu.
Is something up?
Ada apa?
I went to bed early yesterday.
Kemarin aku tidur lebih awal.
I saw your call and called you back.
Lihat panggilanmu, aku langsung telepon balik.
Hello, the number you dialed is powered off.
Maaf, nomor yang Anda tuju sedang tidak aktif.
Old classmate,
Teman lama.
you're here so early to see me.
Pagi-pagi sudah datang mencariku.
Do you remember?
Masih ingat?
The deceased was our high school classmate.
Korban adalah teman SMA kita.
The one you've never forgotten.
Orang yang tak pernah kau lupakan.
Su Ruo.
Su Ruo.
Her body was only found at six this morning.
Mayatnya baru ditemukan jam enam pagi ini.
Cause of death: falling from a building.
Penyebab kematian: jatuh dari gedung.
Yu Xingchen, long time no see.
Yu Xingchen, lama tak bertemu.
You...
Kamu...
were her last client.
Kamu tamu terakhirnya.
No one saw her after she left work yesterday.
Setelah pulang kerja kemarin, tak ada yang melihatnya lagi.
You've been working here all these years.
Kamu sudah kerja di sini selama bertahun-tahun.
It's been quite a few years.
Sudah cukup lama.
Must be tough, right?
Pasti melelahkan, ya?
Everything's tough nowadays.
Sekarang kerja apa pun pasti capek.
Let me treat you to a late-night snack.
Ayo makan malam, aku traktir.
Maybe another day.
Lain kali saja.
I'll ask you out next time.
Nanti aku ajak kamu.
The surveillance matches what he said.
Setelah cek CCTV, ceritanya cocok.
No obvious signs of struggle or injury.
Tak ada luka akibat perkelahian.
Her belongings and wallet weren't missing.
Barang dan dompet korban tidak hilang.
Forensics Division found this at her place.
Unit Forensik menemukan ini di rumahnya.
Did you give this to her?
Kamu yang memberikannya?
Is this letter from you?
Itu surat dari kamu?
We hadn't met for fifteen years before last night.
Sebelum kemarin malam, kita sudah lima belas tahun tak bertemu.
You used cut-out letters to hide your handwriting.
Kamu takut tulisanmu dikenali, jadi pakai huruf tempel?
It wasn't me.
Bukan aku.
Check the fingerprints if you don't believe me.
Kalau tak percaya, cek saja sidik jarinya.
This letter was written with gloves on.
Surat itu ditulis pakai sarung tangan.
No fingerprints could be found on the letter.
Tak ada sidik jari di surat itu.
It really wasn't me.
Sungguh bukan aku.
If you don't believe me, lock me up and interrogate me.
Kalau tak percaya, tahan dan interogasi aku saja.
I don't even know her address.
Aku bahkan tak tahu alamatnya.
How could I mail her this letter?
Bagaimana aku bisa kirim surat itu padanya?
We believe it was just an accident.
Kami menilai ini hanya kecelakaan.
But as police officers,
Tapi sebagai polisi,
it's our duty to ask you for clarification.
menanyaimu adalah tugas kami.
After all, you were the last person she saw.
Kamu orang terakhir yang bertemu dengannya.
She...
Dia...
How did she really die?
Sebenarnya bagaimana dia meninggal?
We're still investigating.
Masih diselidiki.
I want to see where it happened.
Aku ingin lihat tempat kejadian.
Bro, I understand you.
Bro, aku paham perasaanmu.
It's hard when an old classmate has an accident.
Teman lama kena musibah, memang sedih.
I was the one who reported it.
Aku yang melaporkan kasus ini.
I also led the police into the apartment.
Aku juga yang mengantar polisi masuk.
If you have questions, just ask me.
Kalau mau tanya apa pun, silakan.
Did the deceased live in this building?
Korban tinggal di gedung ini?
No, she lived in the building opposite.
Tidak, di gedung seberang.
This is an old neighborhood.
Kompleks ini sudah tua.
There aren't many cameras outside.
CCTV di luar sedikit.
Only the area downstairs has surveillance.
Hanya ada di bagian bawah.
Were you on duty the day it happened?
Hari kejadian, kamu yang jaga?
No, it was another guy.
Bukan, ada orang lain.
I heard that on the day of the incident,
Kudengar hari kejadian,
the rooftop door was locked from inside.
Pintu atap terkunci dari dalam.
The girl probably locked it herself.
Sepertinya gadis itu yang mengunci.
She fell from right here.
Dia jatuh dari sini.
You shouldn't stay here too long.
Jangan lama-lama di sini.
I'm heading down now.
Aku turun dulu.
Just yesterday,
Baru kemarin
Su Ruo gently
Su Ruo masih dengan lembut
said so many things to me.
mengatakan banyak hal padaku.
In just half a day,
Dalam setengah hari saja,
she's gone somewhere I can't reach.
dia sudah pergi ke tempat yang tak bisa kucapai.
Was she ever afraid?
Apa dia pernah takut?
When she called me,
Saat dia meneleponku,
what was she thinking?
apa yang ada di pikirannya?
Everyone says you like me.
Semua orang bilang kau suka padaku.
By the way, Yu Xingchen,
Oh ya, Yu Xingchen,
do you still like me?
apakah kau masih suka padaku?
Do you still like me?
Kau masih suka padaku?
I do.
Suka.
At first,
Awalnya,
I thought this was just a dream.
aku kira ini cuma mimpi.
I'm dreaming.
Aku sedang bermimpi.